BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
I'm so bored.
好无趣
-Hey! -Ah, you scared me!
-喂！ -吓死我了
You look like there's no life left in you.
你一副了无生趣的样子
You're at work right now, so pull yourself together.
现在是上班时间 振作一点
-Get it together! -I know I'm at work.
-振作 -我知道现在是上班时间
But I'm tired of organizing data.
可是我厌倦整理资料了
Remember what I told you before?
记得我跟你说过的话吗？
If Branch Inspection is bored, it means there are
分行稽核无聊
no problems at the branches. Right?
就表示分行没问题 对吗？
Exactly.
完全正确
I get that, but…
那个我懂
When I worked as a teller,
可是我在当柜员时
it was busy every day,
每天都好忙
but I was able to make lots of customers happy
可是我能让好多客户满意
and it was so fulfilling…
那种感觉好充实
I miss those days.
好怀念那些日子
You've only been here a month.
你才来这里一个月
Stop getting nostalgic.
别再怀旧了
I'm so tired. Let me rest a bit.
累死我了 让我休息一下
What happened? You worked up a sweat.
怎么了？你累得满身大汗
The Financial Services Agency will be inspecting our banks next week.
金融厅下个星期要来我们银行检查
Inspection?
金融厅检查？
The inspector visits banks,
检查员到银行检查
to check and provide guidance on loans.
检查及指导贷款
You didn't know this? How can you call yourself a banker?
你不知道啊？你还算是银行职员吗？
Of course, I know about that.
那个我当然知道
It's an inspection to assess the borrowers
那个检查是要评估
and the details of the loan agreement.
贷款人和贷款协议的细节
-Right? -That's right.
-对吧？ -没错
But I've never experienced financial inspection before.
可是我没遇过金融检查
Well, out of the 750 branches nationwide,
全日本750个分行中
only ten or so branches are inspected.
只有十个左右会接受检查
I guess it's like winning a lottery.
我猜那就像中彩票
But you never know when they will come,
但是不知道他们什么时候会来
so even the smallest of the branches have to be prepared.
即使是最小的分行也必须做好准备
What do you prepare?
要准备什么？
Check to make sure pages aren't missing from the loan files,
确定贷款文件没有缺页
and organizing data.
整理资料
-Also creating additional data. -That's a lot of work.
-还有创造出更多资料 -好多工作
All right, I'll be heading back.
好 我要回去了
Oh, Mr. Shibasaki. I'll be stopping by the Nakano Branch before work next Monday.
芝崎次长 下星期一上班前 我会去一下中野分行
Nakano Branch is where the two of you used to work, right?
你们两个以前待过中野分行 对吧？
Yeah.
对
-You still have some unfinished business? -Somewhat.
-你还有没弄完的事？ -多多少少
Then I want to go to the Nakano Branch too.
我也想去中野分行
That's not necessary. I'll go by myself.
不用 我自己去
I want to see everyone too.
我也想去看看大家
-It's not a reunion. -Soma, what are you going there for?
-又不是参加聚会 -相马 你去那里做什么？
-It's my seal… -Seal?
-是我的印章 -印章？
I forgot to stamp it on something.
我有东西忘了盖章
A stamp oversight?
印鉴疏失？
No way, Mr. Soma.
不会吧？相马
The Section Chief of the Sales Division?
营业课长忘了盖章
-Making such a rookie mistake? -You little…
-犯下菜鸟才犯的错误 -你这家伙
I'm sure you'll be feeling a little ashamed,
我相信你会觉得有点丢脸
so I'll go along with you.
所以我跟你一起去
That's not necessary.
没有必要
Yeah, Ms. Hanasaki should go too.
没错 花琦小姐也应该去
-What? -Thank you very much!
-什么？ -太感谢了
We never know what she'll do if we leave her alone.
单独留她下来 不知道她会搞出什么
Yes! I finally get to visit the Nakano Branch again.
太好了 终于又可以去中野分行
I'm so excited.
好期待
I'm sure everyone will be so surprised,
相信大家会很吃惊
to see how refined I've become after moving to headquarters.
看我调到总部后变得这么优雅
-Refined? Who? Where? -Everywhere!
-优雅？谁？哪里？ -全身上下
What? Mr. Soma! And Ms. Hanasaki!
相马先生和花琦小姐
-Hey. -Mr. Nagase!
-嗨 -永濑先生
-Long time no see. -Hello.
-好久不见 -你们好
-How have you been? -Pretty good.
-还好吗？ -很好
Are you inspecting our branch today?
你们今天来我们分行稽核吗？
No, it's not for an inspection… Stop looking at me like that.
我们不是来稽核的 不要那样看我
We're here to run an errand.
我们是来办事的
Ms. Hanasaki, you got prettier.
花琦小姐变得更漂亮了
Oh! I guess you can say that.
我想你这么说应该没错
See? I told you so.
看吧？我就跟你说吧？
You ever heard of social etiquette?
你没听过礼貌性的赞美吗？
Everyone at the branch was saying that Mr. Soma and Ms. Hanasaki
分行里的人都说相马先生和花琦小姐
is a very unexpected pair,
是意想不到的组合
but you two seem like great partners.
不过两位似乎是很棒的搭档
-As if.
-最好是
See?
看吧？
-Stop copying me. -I wasn't.
-别学我说话 -我才没有
How nostalgic.
好怀念呀
Like I said, it's only been a month and a half.
我说了 才过了一个半月
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Don't tell me…
不会吧？
Excuse me… what's going on?
请问是怎么回事？
I'm Aota, the Chief Inspector of Financial Services.
我是金融厅主任检查员青田
I'm here to inspect.
我来检查
Our branch?
我们分行吗？
Please open the door.
请开门
Yes.
是
Mr. Soma, is this…
相马 这是…
It seems like we came here at a bad time.
我们似乎来得不是时候
Financial inspection.
金融检查
We will check everyone's bags.
我们会检查所有人的袋子
Please line up.
请排好队
Open your bag.
打开袋子
Excuse me.
抱歉
Whoa.
哇
They even check the contents of your bag during the financial inspection?
金融检查竟然还检查你的袋子
It reminds me of the bag check at school.
让我想起学校的书包检查
But it's nothing that simple.
可没那么简单
-You can't take business cards home. -I'm sorry.
-名片不能带回家 -对不起
Why can't you take those out of the branch?
那个为什么不能带出分行？
Business cards are customer information too,
名片也是客户资料
so they're not allowed to leave the bank.
所以不允许离开银行
Why is this in your bag?
这个为什么会在你袋子里？
I wanted to write the proposal at home.
我想在家里写提案书
That's not allowed.
不行
Sometimes it backfires being hardworking like that.
有时候工作太拼会有反效果
Okay, that's done. Next person.
可以了 下一位
Comics and games are okay?
漫画和游戏机没关系？
If this was a school, that would be confiscated.
要是在学校 那些会被没收
Like I said, it's not a school bag check.
我说了 这不是书包检查
Now we will check inside the desks.
现在要检查办公桌
Unlock it.
开锁
Hurry.
快点
They even check inside the drawers?
连抽屉都检查
How strict.
真严格
Why is this here?
这个为什么在这里？
You have to take your keys back home.
钥匙必须带回家
Isn't it better to leave the keys
钥匙留在桌上不是比较好吗？
at the desk so you don't lose them?
这样就不会不见了
Then anyone can open it.
那样每个人都能打开抽屉
-What's the point of locking it? -Right…
-那还上锁干什么？ -也对
Listen up, everyone.
都听好了
Banks have a tendency to
银行喜欢藏匿
hide things that are inconvenient.
会造成麻烦的东西
-Don't go easy on them! -Yes, sir.
-不要轻易放过 -是
What's with him?
他有什么毛病啊？
He's treating the bank like a villain.
对待银行像对待罪犯
Lower your voice.
小声一点
Why do you have cash here?
这里为什么有零钱？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Whose passbook is this?
这是谁的存折？
-Whose seal is this? -Uh…
-这是谁的印章？ -嗯
This isn't yours, right?
不是你的 对吧？
What's this?
这是什么？
It's my personal laptop.
是我自己的电脑
I always take it back home, but…
我都会带回家
It's used for work.
是工作用的
There might be a data breach.
可能泄漏资料
-Take it to investigate. -What…
-拿去调查 -什么？
How horrible. They even take away your personal laptop?
太可怕了 甚至连你的电脑都拿走
They don't usually go that far.
他们通常不会那么过分
Soma, Ms. Hanasaki.
相马 花琦小姐
-Branch Manager Makino. -Nice to see you again.
-经理 -真高兴又见到你
What a hassle this has become.
这里变得这么混乱
I didn't think the Financial Services would inspect our branch.
我没想到金融厅竟然会检查我们分行
And for Aota to come, of all people.
而且还是青山过来
Is he that famous?
他那么出名吗？
Yeah, he lives to harass banks.
对 他活着就是为了骚扰银行
He's a notorious inspector known for nitpicking
他是恶名昭彰的检查员 以吹毛求疵闻名
every detail.
所有细节都不放过
Yeah. He seems unpleasant.
他似乎很讨人厌
-Lower your voice-- -Who's unpleasant?
-小声点啦 -谁讨人厌了 ？
It's nice to see you again, Branch Manager Makino.
牧野经理 很高兴又见面了
Hello.
你好
I have to thank you for the last time we met.
上次与你见面的事 我必须谢谢你
It's nice to see you again.
很高兴又见面了
Oh, and I forgot to mention that
忘了告诉你
I've become a Chief Inspector now.
我现在是主任检查员
Please go easy on us.
请手下留情
Who are they?
他们是什么人？
They're Branch Inspectors.
他们是分行稽核员
-I'm Soma. -I'm Hanasaki.
-我是相马 -我是花琦
From headquarters…
总部来的
Just try not to get in our way.
不要妨碍我们做事
Yes, of course.
那当然
But banks sure have changed a lot,
不过银行还真的变了很多
or should I say they've become lax.
或者应该说变得不严谨了
How interesting to see a young lady in Branch Inspection.
看到有年轻女孩当分行稽核员 真有意思
I was a teller here until last March.
我在这里当柜员 一直到今年3月
Teller?
柜员？
That explains it.
难怪
I'm sure you were good at sitting at the window
我相信你擅长坐在柜台前
and smiling.
带着微笑
With all due--
恕我直…
Don't do it. Bear it.
别说了 忍住
We're done inspecting the desks.
办公桌检查完了
Okay.
好
Branch Manager.
经理
Please give us the top 20 companies your branch is financing.
请交出你们分行 正在融资的前20家公司
I understand.
了解
-Section Chief Kimura. -Yes.
-木村课长 -是
Numabukuro Kensetsu.
沼仓建造
Saginomiya Butsuryu.
佐木宫物流
Hashiba Corporation. Kawashima Jouzou.
桥场公司、川岛酿造
Kawazoe Creates. Uchikoshi Seiyaku.
河添创意、内越制药
Tougou Community. NKN Entertainment.
头沟社区、ＮＫＮ娱乐
We will do a thorough investigation now.
我们现在要进行彻底调查
To check every corner of how your branch
确认你们分行的每个角落
is working.
如何运作
Bring all the files you pick up.
带着所有你们挑出的文件
-And the copy machine. -Yes, sir.
-还有影印机 -是 长官
Would you like us to help you out?
需要我们帮忙吗？
Yes, please.
好 拜托了
I'm sorry to drag you into this.
很抱歉让你们卷进这件事
Let's pull together as a team
我们是一个团队 一起努力
and make it through this financial investigation.
度过这次金融检查
It's so heavy.
好重
-It's so heavy. -What are you doing?
-好重 -你在搞什么呀？
You were full of energy a while ago.
刚刚还生龙活虎的
Mr. Soma, you offered to help first.
相马 是你说要帮忙的
Hurry up or we won't finish.
快点 不然做不完
All right!
好
Check for any changes.
贷款协议如果有更动
-In loan agreements, focus on the bonds. -Yes, sir.
-注意保证金 -是 长官
Don't overlook any borrower numbers.
不要忽略任何与贷款人有关的数字
-Especially repayments and use of funds. -Yes, sir.
-还款和资金运用 -是 长官
This is the nitpicking inspection that he's notorious for?
这就是他恶名昭彰的 吹毛求疵检查吗？
Yeah, he checks the details of every single loan.
对 每一笔贷款他都追根究底
If there's even a minor issue,
就算只是一个小问题
he'll do a thorough investigation on it.
他也会对它彻底调查
That Chief Inspector seems stubborn and persistent.
那个主任检查员看起来顽固又难搞
Can you take your personal conversation outside?
你们要聊天可以出去吗？
Lady from headquarters,
总部来的小姐
didn't I tell you not to get in our way?
我没告诉你们别妨碍我们调查吗？
I'm sorry.
对不起
Please let me know if there's anything I can do.
有什么需要 请告诉我
Anything?
需要啊
Then bring tea for everyone here.
那就帮每个人倒茶吧
Tea?
倒茶？
-You said anything, right? -But…
-你说要帮忙的 不是吗？ -可是…
Okay… yes, we'll get the tea right away.
好的 我们立刻拿来
One, two, three… 15 people. Hurry up.
一、二、三… 15个人 快去
-Yes. -Excuse me.
-是 -打扰了
Mr. Shindo, did you call for me?
真藤常务 您找我吗？
Yes.
对
It seems like the Nakano Branch is getting inspected.
中野分行好像正在接受检查
Yes.
是
Why are they inspecting a small branch like Nakano?
为什么会检查中野那样的小分行呢？
Do you have any information regarding this?
你对这件事有任何了解吗？
No, nothing in particular…
没有 没有特别的
I see.
这样啊
Nothing at all?
完全没有吗？
I don't know if this will be useful information,
我不确定这个消息有没有用
but the Nakano Branch is
不过检查中野分行的
being inspected by Chief Inspector Aota.
是主任检查员青田
Aota?
青田？
It's strange,
那就怪了
that Aota would choose to go to the Nakano Branch.
青田竟然选择去中野分行
There aren't any problematic, or large loan contracts there.
那里没有任何有问题的贷款案 或大型贷款案
That's strange.
真是奇怪
It would be a hassle if they do some faultfinding in order to
要是他们像对榛名银行那样故意找茬
issue us a business improvement order like they did with Haruna Bank.
给我们下业务改善令 那就麻烦了
Yes.
是
And then…
还有
What?
怎样？
Soma and Hanasaki from Branch Inspection just so happened
分行稽核班的相马和花琦
to be at the Nakano Branch for an errand.
刚好去中野分行处理事情
-Branch Inspection? -They decided to stay.
-分行稽核班？ -他们决定要
To help the Nakano Branch handle the inspection.
留在中野分行帮忙银行协助这次检查
Of all the times to let them go there…
偏偏这个时候让他们去那里
What bad timing.
时机也太差了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Good work.
干得好
Let us know if you hear anything.
听到任何消息 让我知道
Yes. I will take my leave now.
是 那我回去了
Shibasaki.
芝崎
-You're sweating. -Oh?
你在冒汗
Is it that hot in here?
这里面那么热吗？
N… no, not at all. I'll be going now.
不会 我这就走了
The temperature is just right.
温度刚刚好
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NAKANO BRANCH
（东京第一银行中野分行）
Not only is that Chief Inspector really unpleasant,
那位主任检查员不仅让人讨厌
he's also super demanding.
要求还超级多
Mai!
舞！
Aki! Keiko!
亚纪 惠子
Long time no see.
好久不见
-I missed you guys. -How dramatic.
-我好想你们 -太夸张了
We were together at Mika's wedding.
我们还一起参加实花的婚礼
I know, but it feels like it was long ago.
我知道 可是感觉那是好久以前的事
I miss the days when I was working here.
我想念以前在这里工作的日子
-You're here for the financial inspection? -No, it was a coincidence.
-你是因为金融检查过来的吗？ -不是 那是碰巧
But I somehow ended up helping with the inspection.
不过最后我却在帮忙
-Mai, aren't you tired? -A little.
-舞 你不累吗？ -有一点
When you were a teller, you looked so sharp and worked so hard
你做柜员时犀利又拼命
that people called you "Nakano Branch's number one teller."
大家说你是中野分行柜员第一名
Why is everything in the past tense?
为什么都成过去式了？
Do I look that worn out?
我看起来那么憔悴吗？
Not really,
那倒没有
but you're losing your femininity.
可是你失去了你的女人味
Losing my femininity…
失去了我的女人味？
Ever since I went to Branch Inspection, I'm surrounded by men.
我在分行稽核班都被男人包围
That's great. You're the only girl there.
真好 你是那里唯一的女生
Find an elite at headquarters.
在总部找一个精英
-Start going out with him. -There are lots of men.
-然后跟他交往 -那里男人很多
But they're not elite, or boyfriend material.
但都不是菁英或当男朋友的料
They're plain, and stuffy.
他们平淡又无趣
But a flower doesn't live long, so you have to do your best.
但是好花开不久 你得卯足劲
The flower at a bank is the teller, huh?
银行里的花是柜员
I need to do something.
我需要行动
Listen. No matter how small the error,
听好 不论错误有多小
don't overlook it, and make sure you report it.
都不能忽略 务必上报
Dig everything up.
挖出所有错误
Mr. Aota, we found this in this laptop.
青田先生 在财务部某人的电脑里
-It belongs to someone in Finance. -What?
-找到这个 -什么？
I see.
知道了
This is interesting.
这个有意思
Thank you for helping us out today.
谢谢你们今天来帮忙
I haven't been doing much.
我没做什么
-Right? -Yeah.
-对吧？ -对
It seems like you were well prepared, so I'm sure
看起来 你们做了完善的准备
you'll be fine.
我相信不会有事的
Yeah…
是
What's the matter?
有什么问题吗？
There's actually a file that I'm hiding.
其实我藏了一批文件
Hiding a file?
藏文件？
It's nothing that shocking.
没什么好大惊小怪的
Every branch has a couple of these.
每间分行都有一两件
-Stuff they don't want management knowing. -But a hidden file…
-不希望管理部门知道的事 -可是藏文件…
Numbers from financial statements and business plans
财报与商业计划书里的数字
aren't enough to decide on a loan.
不足以对贷款案做决定
But Financial Services has a hard time understanding that concept.
但是金融厅就是无法理解
So we have to keep those files away from the prying eyes
所以我们才要让这些文件
of the finance inspectors.
不被金融检查官看到
I see.
原来如此
Branch Manager.
经理
The inspectors are heading to the warehouse.
检查员往仓库去了
What?
什么？
-What is this? -How horrible.
-这是做什么？ -太可怕了
We found it!
找到了！
What's this about, Branch Manager Makino?
牧野经理 这是怎么回事？
That is…
那个是…
From what I can see, these are files related to loans.
就我看来 这些文件与贷款有关
You were hiding these here?
你把这些藏在这里？
This is clearly an evasion of inspection.
显然是规避检查
It's a big problem.
这是大问题
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
But I believe it's a mistake.
不过我相信这是误会
We'll find out when we check what's inside.
等我们检查内容就知道了
We'll scrutinize these files now.
我们现在就仔细检查这些文件
-Take them. -Yes.
-带走 -是
I didn't think they'd search here too.
我没想到他们也会搜这里
They trashed this entire place
他们把这里搞得一团乱
and left without cleaning up.
没有整理好就走了
Is the file that bad?
那个文件那么糟吗？
Most of those files were here just to be on the safe side,
放在这里的大部分是安全起见
but there's one file
但是有一个文件
that may not pass the debtor classification.
可能无法通过债务人分类
Which company?
哪家公司？
There must be some suspicious activities going on
这间分行一定进行着可疑活动
here at this branch for you to be hiding these files.
才会藏这些文件
Not at all. We have nothing to hide.
完全没有 我们没有不可告人的事
Then you're saying that these files were not hidden?
你是说这些文件不是被藏起来吗？
That's right.
没错
Then what is this?
那这是什么？
Nogata Giken.
野方技研
The financial statement shows that they've been in the red for six terms.
财报显示他们已经有六期处于赤字
Yes, but their business is slowly on the rise.
对 但是他们的生意正缓慢有起色
-It's clear if you see-- -It doesn't match with the business plan.
-很明显可以从… -这和商业计划书不符
You made a bad financial decision.
你做了不良的财务决策
If you will take a look at their growth rate,
如果看他们的成长速率
you'll see that they're still recoverable.
可以看出贷款还是能收回的
It seems like
看起来
Branch Manager Makino isn't understanding the problem.
牧野经理还搞不清楚问题
What I'm talking about is the fact that
我现在说的是
Nogata Giken is behind their payments by three months.
野方技研拖欠还款三个月
We are keeping an eye on--
我们正密切注意…
You need to do more than keep an eye on them.
你需要做的不仅仅是密切注意
They are at risk of bankruptcy.
他们有破产的危险
I wonder if they're all right.
他们没事吧？
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
-How is it in there? -I have no idea.
-里面怎么样了？ -我不知道
I see…
这样啊
Things turned into a big problem.
演变成大问题了
Yeah.
对
Mr. Nagase.
永濑先生
Just between you and me, how bad is the file
这个我们两个私下说就好
that was being hidden?
那个藏起来的文件有多糟糕？
How bad?
多糟糕吗？
Will the branch be in big trouble if they find out?
他们发现的话 分行会有大麻烦吗？
Maybe.
可能会
I see…
这样啊
I'm so worried.
我好担心
Wait.
等等
By the way, where did Mr. Soma go?
相马去哪里了？
-Take care of those. -Okay.
-那些交给你 -好
If they're in danger of bankruptcy,
如果他们有破产的危险
it will be damaging to your branch.
将会造成你们分行的损失
You will have to take responsibility for it.
你要为此承担责任
Yes.
请进
-Excuse me. -What is it?
-打扰了 -什么事？
You're not supposed to be here.
你不应该在这里
I'm sorry, but this is an urgent matter.
很抱歉 不过这是紧急事件
Branch Manager.
经理
-Really? -Yes.
-真的吗？ -是
What are you two whispering?
你们两个在窃窃私语什么？
Nogata Giken's late payments will be paid off.
野方技研迟付的款项将会付清
What?
什么？
WRITTEN CONSENT
（同意书）
-What is this? -Nogata Giken.
-这是什么？ -野方技研
It owns a facility in the prime location of Kamakura.
在镰仓的黄金地段有设施
We were in talks to have them sell that land
我们和他们谈判卖掉那块地
in order to secure our funds.
以确保我们的资金
The President gave his approval just now.
他们总裁刚刚同意了
What?
什么？
With this, Nogata Giken
有了这个
is no longer in danger of bankruptcy.
野方技研就不再有破产危险
WRITTEN CONSENT
（同意书）
It ended.
结束了
-Is everything all right? -Somewhat.
-都还好吧？ -算是吧
Branch Manager Makino.
牧野经理
Yes.
是
Do you have any other files you are hiding?
你还藏了别的文件吗？
No.
没有
If you confess now,
你现在坦白的话
we will consider mitigating certain areas.
某些地方我们会考虑从轻处置
But if we find some irregularities later on,
要是之后让我们找到有违反规定之处
you will pay for it.
你就要付出代价
We have nothing.
没有了
If we find something,
要是被我找到
we will issue a business improvement order, understand?
我们会签发业务改善令 了解吗？
When that happens, we will make sure to report your name.
到时我们一定会举报你
Your life as a banker will be over.
你的银行职涯就结束了
How horrible.
多可怕呀
He just threatened him.
他在恐吓他
What? Is it the lady from Branch Inspection again?
怎么？ 又是这位分行稽核班来的小姐？
Please don't misunderstand,
请不要误会
I'm just doing what's right.
我只是在做对的事
-With all due respect… -Oh no, she said it.
-恕我直言 -糟糕 她又说了
Just because you're an inspector, doesn't mean
你是检查员 并不表示你有权
you have the right to determine a banker's future.
决定银行职员的未来
You're very high-spirited.
你非常勇敢啊
But the one evading the investigation by secretly hiding files,
但是偷藏文件以躲避调查的
is the bank. Am I wrong?
是银行 我说错了吗？
That's…
那是…
If you're a former teller,
如果你之前是柜员
why don't you supervise the girls working at the window.
怎么不去指导 在柜台工作的那些女孩？
Stay out of my business.
少管我的事情
Don't think that this is over.
别以为这样就结束了
I'll show you what happens when you go against
我要让你见识对抗检查员
an inspector.
是什么下场
He's unforgivable!
他不可原谅
What's so great about being an inspector for Financial Services.
当金融厅的检查员有什么了不起？
-She's really riled up today. -Yes.
-她今天真的被激怒了 -没错
Here's your favorite offal stew.
来 你最爱吃的炖内脏
Dad, I'm not a little kid anymore.
爸 我不是小孩子了
You can't put me in a better mood by feeding me my favorite food.
你不能用喂我最爱吃的东西哄我开心
It's delicious.
真好吃
-She smiled. -How simple.
-她笑了 -多简单啊
Today was a tough day.
今天真不容易
The financial inspection started,
金融检查开始
and of all people, Aota is the one in charge.
负责的竟然是青田
He's a lot stricter than I had heard.
他比我听说的更严格
Who knows what he will say tomorrow…
谁知道他明天会说什么
But thank you for helping me today.
不过谢谢你们今天的帮忙
Soma, thank you for helping me with Nogata Giken.
相马 谢谢你帮忙解决野方技研的事
Minamida was the one in charge,
南田是负责人
and he worked hard to negotiate.
他非常努力协商
-But Mr. Makino… -Yeah?
-可是牧野先生 -什么事？
Did something happen with Aota in the past?
你过去和青田有过节吗？
I've been wondering ever since this morning.
今天早上我就在猜想
Well,
这个嘛
back when Aota was a rookie inspector,
青田还是菜鸟检查员时
the inspection style was very tyrannical,
他的检查风格非常粗暴
so I reported it to his boss.
所以我向他的上司举报
And he received a formal warning because of that.
他因此收到正式警告
I heard that he still holds a grudge against me for that.
我听说他对我还怀恨在心
I see.
我懂了
He still resents you for doing that,
他还在憎恨你举报他
and that's why he hates you so much?
那就是他那么讨厌你的原因吗？
I think so.
我想是的
What a piece of work.
真是小人
It's not just his work ethics, but his personality that is nasty too.
他的职业道德和个性都令人讨厌
Eat your offal stew.
吃你的炖内脏
Mr. Makino, eat the offal stew and cheer up.
牧野先生 吃炖内脏 振作起来
-Thank you. -That's on us.
-谢谢 -这个是店里请客
-Sure.
-不客气
But how did they find that?
可是他们是怎么发现的呢？
-That file? -Yeah.
-那个文件吗？ -对
They don't usually search an underground warehouse.
他们通常不会搜查地下室仓库
Yeah, that sure is strange.
确实奇怪
Oh.
对了
Maybe there's an informer within the bank.
也许银行里有泄密者
Informer?
泄密者？
So someone who knew about that warehouse told Aota?
某个知道仓库的人告诉了青田
Yes.
对
But not everyone knows where the files
不过不是每个人都知道
are hidden, right?
文件藏在哪里 对吧？
Everyone in the Financial Department
每个财务部的人
and the Section Chief's would know.
还有课长都知道
Then we won't know who the informer is.
那么我们就无法知道泄密者是谁了
That's right.
没错
I wonder who it is.
我想知道他是谁
Maybe Deputy Manager Tanaka wants to
也许是田中副理
become the Branch Manager.
想当分行经理
That can't be. Mr. Tanaka is such a nice person.
不可能 田中先生是这么好的人
Oh, maybe it's Mr. Kimura, the Section Chief of the Finance Department.
有了 也许是财务部的木村课长
Despite how he looks, Mr. Kimura is very ambitious.
木村先生不管怎么看都野心勃勃
Look at my wife. Isn't she beautiful?
看看我老婆 她是不是很美呀？
Mr. Kimura loves his wife, so I don't think it's him.
木村先生很爱他老婆 我认为不可能是他
It might be Mr. Ishii…
或许是石井先生
He said he can never win against
他说过他打高尔夫
the Branch Manager at golf.
永远赢不了分行经理
But Mr. Ishii is a sweet father of two kids.
可是石井先生是有两个小孩的好爸爸
So there's no way it's him.
不可能是他
What are you saying?
你在自言自语什么呀？
I have no idea.
我想不出来
I doubt he'll end things without a fight.
我怀疑他不会善罢甘休
What?
什么？
I've heard lots of horrible rumors about Aota.
我听过很多关于青田的可怕传言
When Haruna Bank got the business improvement order,
榛名银行收到业务改善令时
they say he fabricated details to make it seem like they evaded inspection.
听说他捏造细节 让榛名银行看起来像逃避检查
-Fabricated? -Yeah.
-捏造？ -对
Just like you said,
就像你说的
we found the hidden files
我们找到了藏起来的文件
but that's not good enough.
不过那个还不够
We couldn't corner Makino.
无法让牧野走投无路
What else is there?
还藏了什么？
At this point, use whatever means possible.
都到这时候了 任何手段都行
Do something yourself.
你自己想办法
What?
你说什么？
You want me to publicize everything?
你想要我把事情都公布吗？
We can't put our guard down tomorrow.
明天我们不能松懈防备
We don't know what dirty tricks he will play.
不知道他会玩什么阴险招数
I wonder what he has up his sleeves.
我想知道他还留了什么后手
Oh.
对了
What would you do, Mr. Soma?
相马 换作是你 你会怎么做？
-What? Me? -Yeah.
-我吗？ -对
If it was me…
如果是我的话…
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NAKANO BRANCH
（东京第一银行中野分行）
MONTHLY FINANCE REPORT
（财务月报表）
BUSINESS REVIVAL PLAN
（商业恢复计划书）
So, you were the informer…
你就是泄密者
Mr. Nagase.
永濑先生
-How? -What if Aota were to plot something?
-怎么会？ -如果青田想耍阴谋诡计
We thought he would try to conceal the investigation files.
我们认为他会想藏匿调查文件
We figured he would make his informer do that.
我们猜他会命令泄密者去做
Before the Finance Department came in.
趁融资课的人进来之前…
I'm sorry.
对不起
Mr. Nagase…
永濑先生
Why are you his informer?
你为什么是他的泄密者？
Were you threatened by Aota?
青田威胁你吗？
Yes.
是
Just as I thought…
果然
Yesterday, when they confiscated my laptop,
昨天他们没收我的电脑
they checked my email…
检查我的电子邮件
They found out that I'm in debt.
发现我有欠债
It seems like you're deep in debt.
看来你负债累累
And since you're also borrowing from loan sharks,
既然你向高利贷借钱
that would disqualify you as a banker.
那你就是不称职的银行职员
If this becomes public,
这件事如果公布出去
it will ruin your future as a banker.
会毁了你作为银行职员的职业生涯
Please… anything but that.
拜托 你要我做什么都行
Then,
那么
give me information that would harm the branch.
告诉我能伤害分行的信息
What?
什么？
That's blackmailing.
那是恐吓
That's something Aota would do.
那是青田会做的事
That's why I told him where the loan files
所以我才告诉他
were hidden.
那些贷款文件藏在哪里
But Aota was not satisfied with that.
可是青田还不满意
That's why
所以
he tried to fabricate a case
他想要捏造
of data concealment.
资料隐匿案
Yes.
对
Mr. Aota called me last night.
昨天晚上青田先生打电话给我
At this point, use whatever means possible.
都到这时候了 任何手段都行
Figure something out on your own.
你自己想办法
No way…
不可能
-I can't do it. -What?
-我不能那么做 -你说什么？
You want me to publicize everything?
你想要我把事情都公布吗？
But…
可是…
Go pull out a loan file that I'm about to tell you.
我会告诉你一个贷款文件 去取出来
-Hide it somewhere. -What?
-然后把它藏起来 -啊
Later, I will pretend I found it.
之后我会假装是我找到的
What?
什么？
He's taking advantage of someone's weakness.
他在利用别人的弱点
He's so dirty!
真下流
It's my fault for succumbing to his blackmail.
屈服于他的威胁是我的错
I…
我…
I'm disqualified as a banker.
我没有资格当银行职员
Mr. Nagase, let's go apologize to Branch Manager Makino.
永濑先生 我们去向牧野经理道歉
If you explain everything, I'm sure he'll understand.
你把一切解释清楚 我相信他会理解
No, that won't be enough.
不 那还不够
Mr. Soma.
相马
Nagase.
永濑
If you really regret what you've done,
如果你真的对你所做的事感到懊悔
it's not too late.
现在为时不晚
Go and tell Aota that you won't do it.
去拒绝青田
Isn't that what you should do right now?
这不是你现在应该做的吗？
Yes.
是
But I want to punish that
但是我想要
Chief Inspector somehow.
惩罚那个主任检查员
Isn't there a way to do that?
难道没有办法吗？
Stop it.
别说了
What?
什么？
For once, the bank is not at fault.
难得这次错不在银行
We'll just have to let it go.
我们就让事情过去吧
No way.
休想
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NAKANO BRANCH
（东京第一银行中野分行）
Please bring out the loan files of customers that I call out.
请把我说的客户贷款文件拿出来
Okay.
好的
Tokyo Sougou Setsubi.
东京太阳能设备
Hinoyama Print.
日野山影印
Touou Juutaku.
头王建筑
Food Real.
食物不动产
Total Bill Support.
全能债务协商
Mikimoto Kenzai.
御木本健康器材
Hinode Sekizai.
日之初石材
Sakaue Mokuzai.
荣上木材
Fujimi Solution.
富士见液剂
-Mr. Aota. -Yes?
-青田先生 -怎样？
There are no problems with any of the loan files.
所有贷款文件都没有问题
What?
你说什么？
That can't be. There has to be a missing file.
不可能 肯定有文件不见了
-There's nothing missing. -It's all here.
-没有东西不见 -全部都在这里
That bastard.
那个混蛋
What's going on?
怎么回事？
I…
我…
cannot betray the bank anymore.
不能再背叛银行了
Do you want me to publicize your debt?
你要我将你的债务公诸于世吗？
Do you understand
你知道吗？
that I can easily use my power
用我的权力
to fire a banker like you.
开除你这样的银行职员 是轻而易举的事
Do whatever it takes
不惜一切代价去做
so that I can blame the Branch Manager for obstructing inspection.
这样我就可以归咎分行经理妨碍检查
-Got it? -I can't do it.
-懂吗？ -我不能这么做
I won't do it.
我是不会做的
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Damn it.
可恶！
Oh no, I didn't know that the finance inspection would be going on today too.
糟糕 我不知道今天也要金融检查
What's the matter?
怎么了吗？
Well…
那个…
Mr. Takagi from the Finance Department asked me to
其实融资课的高木先生
hold onto something.
要我藏一个东西
Something?
什么东西？
I don't know what it is, but it's a loan file.
不清楚 我只知道那是贷款文件
He was supposed to have dealt with it by last week,
他应该要上星期处理完的
but he said he forgot.
可是他说他忘了
He said, "If Financial Services
他说要是被金融厅发现
finds out about this, it will trouble the whole branch."
会为整个分行带来麻烦
What? Why did you let him leave it with you?
你怎么会让他把东西留在你这里？
-Because… -More importantly,
-因为… -更重要的是
where did you hide that file?
你把文件藏在哪里？
BREAK ROOM
（茶水间）
It's at…
我把它藏在…
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NAKANO BRANCH
（东京第一银行中野分行）
Everything is balanced. Thank you very much.
全部结平 谢谢大家
Thank you.
谢谢
Good work, everyone.
-做得好 -大家都很棒
-I'm so hungry. -What do you want to eat?
-我好饿 -你想吃什么？
Will you treat me…
你要请我吗？
Who is Keiko Shimazaki?
岛崎惠子是哪一位？
That's me.
是我
Show me your locker.
让我看你的置物柜
What?
什么？
-Why Keiko? -What?
-为什么是惠子？ -什么？
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
We received information from an inside informant
我们收到内部检举
that there is an important loan file hidden in the locker
有一份重要贷款文件
of Keiko Shimazaki.
藏在岛崎惠子的置物柜里
What?
什么？
This is not right.
这样做是不对的
She's in the Sales Department, not Finance.
她在营业课 不是融资课
It'll all clear up once we check her locker.
检查完她的置物柜就都明白了
Please open your locker.
请打开你的置物柜
Wait a minute. Even if it's an inspection,
等一下 就算是检查
there has to be a line somewhere.
也该有个限度吧？
Oh, it's you again.
又是你
I can report this as obstruction.
我可以举报你妨碍检查
-We don't care. -Hanasaki.
-我不在乎 -花琦
There's no point talking to you.
和你说话没有意义
Branch Manager, didn't I tell you yesterday
经理 我昨天没告诉你吗？
that I will not let you go if there are
要是有藏匿的贷款文件
any hidden loan files.
我是不会放过你的
Be prepared.
做好准备
Give me your keys.
把钥匙给我
Over here.
在这里
Inspector Aota.
青田检查员
You should stop right now.
你现在应该住手
You have no right to tell me what to do.
你没有权力告诉我怎么做
Please stop!
请住手！
NOW HANDLING IC CASH CARD!
（立即办理ＩＣ现金卡）
Why isn't it here?
为什么没有？
Let's go.
我们走
Wait a minute.
等一下
You ransacked a female employee's locker,
你翻完女性员工的置物柜
and you're just going to leave?
就想这样走了？
Apologize before you leave.
道歉完再走
Listen. There's a hidden file somewhere in this branch.
听好 这间分行的某处藏了文件
We're just trying to find that.
我们只是想把它找出来
Is that wrong?
有什么错？
Does an inspection justify everything?
检查就能合理化一切吗？
What?
怎么样？
You said that an inside informant
你说有内部的人检举
told you about a hidden file,
告诉你有藏匿的文件
but is that even true in the first place?
但是那一开始就是真实的吗？
What?
你说什么？
Did you set me up?
你设计我？
Yes.
是
There are no files hidden in this branch.
这个分行里没有藏匿的文件
What?
什么？
Do you think you'll get away with this?
你以为这件事就这样算了吗？
You were resorting to using dirty tricks,
你使用卑鄙的手段
so we just played accordingly.
我们只是有样学样
Dirty tricks? What are you talking about?
卑鄙手段？你在说什么？
Mr. Aota, in order to avenge an old grudge, you were searching
青田先生 你为了报复旧怨
Nakano Branch for a big mistake that could bring down
在中野分行搜索
Branch Manager Makino.
能击垮牧野经理的重大错误
When you couldn't find anything,
当你找不到任何错误时
you threatened our employee
便威胁我们的银行职员
to make him hide an important file, right?
要他藏匿一个重要文件 对吧？
I don't know about that.
我不知道你说的事
Mr. Nagase told us everything.
永濑先生已经把一切都告诉我们了
He said he's ready to testify anytime.
他说他准备好了随时出庭作证
Will you still deny it?
你还要否认吗？
Idiot…
笨蛋
That's just his imagination.
那只是他幻想的
Between a bank employee
一个是银行职员
and a Chief Inspector for the Financial Services Agency,
一个是金融厅的主任检查员
who will they believe?
法官会相信谁？
Are you done now?
你说完了吗？
What happened to your fiery attitude?
你嚣张的气焰呢？
First of all, there isn't any proof
首先 你说的话
to back up what you've said.
没有任何证据支持
Do you want me to publicize your debt?
你要我将你的债务公诸于世吗？
Do you understand that I can easily use my power
你知道我可以轻而易举
to fire a banker like you.
用我的权力开除你这样的银行职员
Mr. Soma…
相马
Do whatever it takes
不惜一切代价去做
so that I can blame the Branch Manager for obstructing inspection.
这样我就可以归咎分行经理妨碍检查
Got it?
懂吗？
Mr. Aota.
青田先生
This counts as proof, right?
这算是证据吧？
I had heard bad rumors about you.
我听过关于你的负面传言
So I knew that you would object to whatever we say.
我知道不论我们说什么 你都会反对
So I had Nagase record the conversation just in case.
为了以防万一 我请永濑录下你们的对话
It's some kind of mistake.
那是误会
I conducted a legitimate inspection…
我执行的是合法检查
Legitimate inspection?
合法检查？
Can you say the same thing in front of the Minister for Financial Services?
你敢在金融担当大臣面前 再说一次吗？
Well?
你敢吗？
Shut up!
闭嘴！
No, I won't!
我不要！
You misused your authority
你滥用职权
to trap a banker to avenge your personal grudge.
设计银行职员以报私仇
That's wrong!
那是错的
You are wrong as an inspector… no,
身为检查员 你错了 不对
as a human being!
身为一个人 你错了
And
还有
you stormed into
你冲进女性休息室
the women's locker room and didn't apologize for causing a ruckus.
却不为你引起的骚动道歉
You're a despicable man!
你是个卑劣的男人
Damn.
可恶！
-I did it. -What?
-成功了 -什么？
-Keiko, you were amazing! -I'm so happy.
-惠子 你太厉害了 -我好开心！
-Why didn't you ask me? -I'm so glad!
-你怎么不找我？ -我好高兴
-Hold on a minute. -Cheers!
-等一下 -开心！
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
All right,
太好了
cheers!
干杯！
That was impressive.
真令人印象深刻
I can't believe that was all an act.
我不敢相信那都是演出来的
I'm sorry.
对不起
But we wouldn't have been able to get that
可是不这么做
sly inspector if we hadn't done that.
根本抓不到那个狡猾的检查员
But I'm glad he fell for it.
我很高兴他上当了
It was hit or miss.
那要碰运气
Mr. Soma, we wouldn't have had to work so hard
相马 你应该早点告诉我录音的事
if you had told us about that recording.
我们就不用那么辛苦了
I was waiting for a chance to submit it to top management.
我在等待时机将录 音交给管理高层
-Oh really? -I still can't believe it.
-真的吗？ -不过我还是无法相信
Coming up with that plan.
你想出那个计划
It's because we had a great actress.
那是因为我们有最佳女演员
Keiko used to be in the drama club.
惠子曾经是戏剧社的
-You didn't know? -How would I know?
-你不知道吗？ -我怎么会知道？
I knew. Good work.
我知道 演得好
I wish I could've seen you act.
真希望我能看到你们演戏
Thank you.
谢谢
It's been a while since I acted in front of a crowd,
我好久没在那么多人面前演戏了
so I was so nervous.
好紧张
I can't believe you didn't tell me.
我不敢相信你们没告诉我
-I was shocked. -I couldn't tell you.
-我吓坏了 -因为要是告诉你
I knew you'd get so nervous.
你会很紧张
I guess you're right.
我猜你说得对
You did so well, Keiko.
惠子 你演得真好
Oh, and where did that black underwear come from?
那条黑色小内裤是哪里来的？
-Oh yeah-- -That was part of the plan too?
-对 -那也在计划里吗？
Is that yours?
那是你的吗？
-No way! -What about the black underwear?
-不可能 -什么黑色内裤？
No, Keiko came up with that on her own.
不是 那是惠子自己想出来的
I didn't know about that either.
那个我也不知道
I ran out and bought it during my break.
我在休息时间跑出去买的
I wanted to make it exciting,
我想让场面更刺激
but was it too much?
可是会太过分吗？
-It was awesome. -All right!
-棒呆了 -好耶
Women are scary.
女人好可怕
They sure are.
一点也没错
Did you say something?
你们说什么？
No.
没有
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
Aota received a disciplinary dismissal.
青田遭到免职
Dismissal?
免职？
Yes. False reporting, blackmail, and misuse of authority.
对 错误报告、恐吓和滥用职权
It was confirmed that he had done something similar
经过证实 他过去也做过
in the past.
类似的事
I never expected that
我真没料到
aggressive inspector to end up like this.
那个凶悍的检查员是这个下场
We got a lucky break,
我们真幸运
but Aota getting dismissed by Financial Services
青田被金融厅免职
is great news for our bank.
对我们银行是大好的消息
But it bothers me that those two people
但是让我心烦的 是那两个分行稽核员
from Branch Inspection
分行稽核班
had a part in this.
也参与其中
If we leave them alone,
要是放任他们不管
those two
那两个人
might become a troublesome existence.
可能成为棘手的人物
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
I'm back.
我回来了
Branch Manager Makino just called.
牧野经理刚刚打电话过来
Really?
什么？
They only received a strict warning for the files that were
他们只因为在仓库找到的文件
found in the warehouse.
收到严厉警告
I'm so glad.
太好了
What about Mr. Nagase?
永濑先生怎么样了？
He's fine too, since Aota got fired.
他没事 因为青田被免职了
But he received a scolding
不过他因为私生活
about his personal life.
受到申斥
I'm sure Mr. Nagase learned his lesson.
我相信永濑先生学到教训了
Yeah, I'm glad it all worked out.
对 我很高兴问题都解决了
-There's nothing to be glad about, Soma. -What?
-相马 没什么好高兴的 -怎么了？
You were gone for two days doing something other than inspection.
你们不在两天 去做不是稽核的工作
These are the inspection sites for you this week.
这些是这个星期的稽核地点
-They piled up. -This many?
-堆了一堆 -这么多？
Stop complaining and get moving.
别抱怨了 赶快行动
Okay.
好的
-Where should we start? -Let's see.
-该从哪里开始呢？ -来看看
-Oh no. -What is it?
-糟糕 -怎么了？
I ended up never stamping my seal
我在中野分行
at the Nakano Branch.
最后还是没盖章
Oh come on, Mr. Soma…
拜托 相马
You're hopeless.
你无药可救了
What were you doing for two days?
这两天你都在做什么？
I'll go there right now.
抱歉 我立刻过去
-I'll go too. -Why are you coming?
-我也去 -你去干嘛？
I'll go with you.
我跟你去
-I'm fine by myself. -I'll come.
-我自己去就行 -我要去
Go to the inspection sites!
去稽核地点！
Okay, bye!
好的 再见
Sexual harassment by a manager?
被分行经理性骚扰？
This wouldn't have happened if you had listened to me.
你要是听我的话 就不会发生这种事
A scandal is prohibited at a bank where we prioritize trust.
银行优先考虑信任 禁止丑闻
I didn't want people to know.
我不想让别人知道
I won't forgive you for ruining her life.
我不会原谅你毁了她的人生